Collection of Individually Donated Bookplates
Yale University Arts Library
Collection of individually donated bookplates
1900-2013
1900-1999
BKP 122
Yale University Arts Library
0.42
(1 box)
This is an artificial collection of individually donated bookplates received since 2010.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired by gift.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This is an artificial collection of individually donated bookplates received since 2010.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically by date of acquisition.
Bookplates; Bookplates; Correspondence
- Bookplates
  Scope and Contents
  Many of the folders also contain correspondence related to the donation and sometimes further information about the bookplates themselves.
  - Bookplate of Julius S. Held, undated; Baskin, Leonard, 1922-2000; 2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Custodial History
    Gift of John Walsh, 2010.
  - Bookplate of F. Peter Swanson, Jr., undated; Swanson, F. Peter; 2 (Box 1, Folder 1a)
    Gift of F. Peter Swanson, MD ('72, '76 Med), 2012.
    Printed by Swanson at the Berkeley Press on a Chandler & Price printing press.
  - Bookplate of Anne Rosenberg, undated; Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971; 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Gift of Richard Lowenstein, 2012.
  - Bookplate of Simon Beattie, 2005; Brett, Simon, 1943-; 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Gift of Simon Beattie, 2012.
  - Bookplate of Lewis Koch, circa 1970; Koch, Lewis, 1949-; 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Gift of Lewis Koch, 2012.
  - Bookplate of Maureen E. Mulvihill, circa 1990; Mulvihill, Maureen Esther; 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Gift of Maureen E. Mulvihill, 2012.
  - Bookplate of Carleton Byron Swift, 2011 undated; Chang, Carlisle, 1921-2001; Bornstein, Dean; 2 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Gift of Claudia Hill, Mrs. Grace Hope Hill, Da'aga Hill Bowman, and Jay Satterfield, 2012.
  - Bookplate of Robert J. Weinberg, 1999 undated; 3 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Gift of Robert J. Weinberg, 2012.
  - Multiple bookplates, undated; 8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Includes bookplates for the following individuals: J. T. Fraser [2 copies], Alexander M. Schindler, Elieser Schindler, Theodore Weicker, Edward Joseph Bowes [3 copies].
  - Multiple bookplates, 1926 undated; 8 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Gift of Richard Lowenstein, 2013.
    Includes bookplates for the following individuals: C. W. & W. J. Berwick [2 copies], Eva Le Gallienne, J. Edward Lumbard, Myron and Elsa Metzenbaum, Carol Ruth and H. R. Shepherd, Eloise Sheldon, and Mara Wharton.
  - Multiple bookplates, 36 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Includes bookplates of the following individuals: James H. Blauvelt, Elihu Chauncey, Herbert Duncan Crouch, Elizabeth Downe, Hilda B. Edwards, H. S. Ehrismann, Virginia C. Fraley, Leo. M. Franklin, Herbert John Gladstone, Richard E. Glass, Betty J. Leary, George J. Molnar, M.D., John Monks, Thomas B. Mosher, Calvin Neff, Angelica Van Vranken Olmstead, Elizabeth A. Otis, Dewey Pils, J. W. F. Podmore, Alfred Robinson, Howard C. Smith, W. S. Summers, Welles, Pliny Jewell Wilson, E. H. Worcester, John and Nancy Worcester, and Unidentified [Don Quixote design].
    Includes bookplates of the following institutions: Adelbert College-Western Reserve University, Brooklyn College Library, de Grey & Ripon, Loomis Institute Library, San Diego College for Women, Sondley Reference Library, Trinity Parish Library-Southport, CT, Yale Medical Library, and Young Women's Christian Association-National Training School.
    Gift of Richard Lowenstein, 2014.
  - Bibliotheca Bibliographica Breslaueriana, 2014 undated; 5 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Includes two copies of the bookplate as well as correspondence and a business card from Michael Laird.
    Gift of Michael Laird, 2014.
  - Multiple bookplates, 17 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Includes bookplates of the following individuals: Rev. Edwin A. Dalrymple, D.D., Charles H. Ferris, Grace Hopper, Catharine and Stanley Miller, Robert V. New, The Oldens, John Quinn, Francis Waring Robinson.
    Grace Hopper plate included the following note by Lowenstein: "Grace Hopper, a U.S. Navy Officer, was also a computer pioneer, hence the zeros and ones. This may be her bookplate."
    Francis Waring Robinson plate included the following note by Lowenstein: "Robinson was a curator at the Detroit Institute of Art. (1907-1985)"
    Also includes bookplates of the following institutions: Alpha Delta Phi (Cornell Chapter) [2 versions], Boys High School Brooklyn, Hampton Library-Bridgehampton, NY, Norwalk Public Library, Pequot Library, South Norwalk Public Library, Treadwell Library-Massachusetts General Hospital, and Westport Public Library.